American Painting Section of the Mounted Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- K (Box 76)
  - Individual Artists (Box 77)
    - Kingman, Doug, 1911-., 6 (Box 79)
    - Kline, Franz, 1910-1962., 49 (Box 79)
      - Undated, 5 (Box 79)
      - 1940-1949, 3 (Box 79)
      - 1950-1959, 25 (Box 79)
      - 1960-1969, 16 (Box 79)
    - Knaths, Karl, 1891-1971., 9 (Box 80)
    - Knight, Ridgway, 1839-1924., 3 (Box 80)
    - Koerner, Henry, 1915-., 11 (Box 80)
    - Krasner, Lee, 1908-1984., 19 (Box 80)
    - Krimmel, John Lewis, 1789-1821., 9 (Box 80)
    - Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974., 11 (Box 80)
    - Krushenick, Nicholas, 1929-., 12 (Box 81)
    - Kuhn, Justus Englehardt, act. 1708- 1717., 5 (Box 81)
    - Kuhn, Walt, 1880-1949., 25 (Box 81)
      - Drawings, 5 (Box 81)
      - Paintings, 20 (Box 81)
    - Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1889-1953., 23 (Box 82)
      - Drawings, 3 (Box 82)
      - Paintings, 20 (Box 82)
- L (Box 82)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "L" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: La., 26 (Box 82)
    - Lacroix, Paul., 2 (Box 82)
    - Lam, Jennett., 1 (Box 82)
    - Lambdin, George., 4 (Box 82)
    - Lamson, Edward., 1 (Box 82)
    - Landeck, Armin., 1 (Box 82)
    - Laning, Edward., 2 (Box 82)
    - Lanyon, Ellen., 1 (Box 82)
    - Lasansky, Mauricio., 1 (Box 82)
    - Lassaw, Ibram., 1 (Box 82)
    - Latrobe, Benjamin Henry., 2 (Box 82)
    - Laufer, Susan., 2 (Box 82)
    - Lawrence, A.A., 1 (Box 82)
    - Lawrie, Alexander j., 1 (Box 82)
    - Lawson, Ernest., 4 (Box 82)
    - Lawson, Lee., 1 (Box 82)
    - Lay, Oliver I., 1 (Box 82)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Le., 27 (Box 83)
    - Leake, Eugene., 1 (Box 83)
    - Leavitt, Joseph Warren., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lebduske, Lawrence H., 1 (Box 83)
    - Le Clear, Thomas., 2 (Box 83)
    - Lee, Joseph., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lee, Sidney., 1 (Box 83)
    - Leggett, Ann., 1 (Box 83)
    - Leighton, Scott., 1 (Box 83)
    - Le Moyne de Morgues, Jacques., 1 (Box 83)
    - Leonard, Bertha., 1 (Box 83)
    - Leonard, Michael., 1 (Box 83)
    - Leslie, Alfred., 3 (Box 83)
    - Lester, William., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lettick, Birney., 3 (Box 83)
    - Le Va, Barry., 1 (Box 83)
    - Levee, John., 1 (Box 83)
    - Levine, Jack., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lewandowski, Henry., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lewis, Henry., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lewitin, Landes., 2 (Box 83)
    - Liljefors, Bruno., 1 (Box 83)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Lo-Ly., 20 (Box 83)
    - Lobdell, Frank., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lockwood, John Ward., 2 (Box 83)
    - Lomas Garza, Carmen., 1 (Box 83)
    - Longo, Robert., 4 (Box 83)
    - Longo, Vincent., 2 (Box 83)
    - Loop, H.A., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lowden, Emily E., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lozowick, Louis., 2 (Box 83)
    - Lund, Jane., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lundeberg, Helen., 2 (Box 83)
    - Lungkwitz, Hermann., 1 (Box 83)
    - Lytle, Richard., 2 (Box 83)
  - Individual Artists (Box 83)
    - Lachaise, Gaston, 1882-1935., 3 (Box 83)
    - LaFarge, John, 1835-1910., 29 (Box 83)
    - Lane, Fitz Hugh, 1804-1865., 14 (Box 84)
    - Lathrop, William Langson, 1859-1938., 3 (Box 84)
    - Laufman, Sidney, 1891-., 4 (Box 84)
    - Lawrence, Jacob, 1917-., 15 (Box 84)
    - Lebrun, Frederico (Rico), 1900-1964., 6 (Box 84)
    - Lee, Doris, 1905-1983., 9 (Box 84)
    - Leutze, Emmanuel, 1816-1868., 5 (Box 85)
    - Lever, Hayley, 1876-1958., 3 (Box 85)
    - Levi, Julian Edwin, 1900-., 5 (Box 85)
    - Levine, Jack, 1915-., 12 (Box 85)
    - Lewitt, Sol, 1928-., 7 (Box 85)
    - Liberman, Alexander, 1912-., 7 (Box 85)
    - Lichtenstein, Roy, 1923-1997., 46 (Box 85)
    - Lie, Jonas, 1880-1940., 6 (Box 86)
    - Lindner, Richard, 1901-1978., 17 (Box 86)
    - Louis, Morris, 1912-1962., 30 (Box 86)
    - Lucioni, Luigi, 1900-., 7 (Box 86)
    - Luks, George, 1866-1933., 28 (Box 86–87)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 20 (Box 87)
      - Individual Cities: Washington D.C., 8 (Box 87)
- M (Box 87)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "M" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ma-Mal., 10 (Box 87)
    - Mackay, 1788-1791., 2 (Box 87)
    - Mackay, William Andrew, 20th c., 1 (Box 87)
    - Macmonnies, Fred W., 1863-?, 1 (Box 87)
    - Maentel, Jacob, 1763-1863., 3 (Box 87)
    - Mainardi, Patricia, 1942-?., 1 (Box 87)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Mam-Mas., 21 (Box 87)
    - Mangold, Robert, 1937-., 1 (Box 87)
    - Mangold, Sylvia Plimack, 1938-., 3 (Box 87)
    - Manigault, Middleton, 1887-1922., 2 (Box 87)
    - Manley, Phyllis, 1928-?., 1 (Box 87)
    - Marca-Relli, Conrad, 1913-?., 3 (Box 87)
    - Marisol, 1930-., 1 (Box 87)
    - Marsicano, Nicholas, 20th c., 1 (Box 87)
    - Martens, J.W., 19th c., 1 (Box 87)
    - Martin, Agnes, 1911-., 3 (Box 87)
    - Martini, J. de, 1896-?., 1 (Box 87)
    - Mason, Alice Trumbull, 1904-1971., 1 (Box 87)
    - Mason, Emily, 1932-., 1 (Box 87)
    - Mason, W. Sanford, 1932-., 1 (Box 87)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Mat-Maz., 16 (Box 88)
    - Mathews, Lucia Kleinhams, 1870-1955., 1 (Box 88)
    - Mathieu, Georges, 1921-?., 1 (Box 88)
    - Matta-Clark, Gordon, 1943-1978., 1 (Box 88)
    - Mattern, Karl, 1892-?., 1 (Box 88)
    - Matteson, Thompkins Harrison, 1813-1884., 3 (Box 88)
    - Maxwell, John, 1934-., 2 (Box 88)
    - May, E., 19th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Mayr, Christian, 1805-1890., 1 (Box 88)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Mc., 12 (Box 88)
    - McBride, Henry, 1869-1962., 1 (Box 88)
    - McCartin, Jan, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - McCloskey, William J., 19th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - McCoy, Ann, 1946-., 1 (Box 88)
    - McEnfee, Jervis, 1828-1891., 1 (Box 88)
    - McLaughlin, John, 1898-1976., 2 (Box 88)
    - McLean, Richard, 1934-., 1 (Box 88)
    - McLeary, Kindred, 1901-?., 1 (Box 88)
    - McNeil, George, 1909-?., 3 (Box 88)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Me., 13 (Box 88)
    - Meeker, Joseph Rusling, 1827-1889., 2 (Box 88)
    - Mehring, Howard, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Melcarth, Edward, 1915-?., 2 (Box 88)
    - Mercer, William, 18th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Merkin, Richard, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Merrett, Susan, 19th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Merrild, Knud, 1894-?., 1 (Box 88)
    - Merrill, J.F, 19th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Merritt, Anna Lea, 1844-1930., 1 (Box 88)
    - Meyerowitz, Theresa Bernstein, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Meyr, C., 19th c., 1 (Box 88)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Mi., 13 (Box 88)
    - Midgette, Willard, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Mihail, Simonoff, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Mill, W.R., 19th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Miller, William R., 1818-1893., 1 (Box 88)
    - Millet, Francis D., 1846-1912., 3 (Box 88)
    - Millman, Edward, 1907-1964., 2 (Box 88)
    - Milosevich, Paul, 1936-., 2 (Box 88)
    - Mitchell, Bruce, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Mo., 21 (Box 88)
    - Moeller, Louis C., 1855-1930., 1 (Box 88)
    - Moller, Hans, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Mommer, Paul, 1899-?., 2 (Box 88)
    - Moore, Harriet, 18th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Moore, Nelson Augustus, 1824-1902., 1 (Box 88)
    - Mopp, Maximilian, 1885-1954., 1 (Box 88)
    - Moppett, Ross, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Mora, F. Luis, 1874-1940., 2 (Box 88)
    - Moran, Edward, 1829-1901., 1 (Box 88)
    - Morris, Carl, 1911-?., 1 (Box 88)
    - Morris, Robert, 1931-., 2 (Box 88)
    - Morse, Charlotte, 19th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Moses, Anna Mary ("Grandma"), 1860-1961., 3 (Box 88)
    - Moses, Ed, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Moskowitz, Robert, 20th c., 1 (Box 88)
    - Mothner, Carol, 1943-., 1 (Box 88)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Mu-My., 12 (Box 89)
    - Mullican, Lee, 20th c., 1 (Box 89)
    - Munger, Gilbert, 1836-1903., 1 (Box 89)
    - Munos, Rie, 1921-?., 1 (Box 89)
    - Murch, Walter, 1907-?., 1 (Box 89)
    - Murphy, Gerald, 1888-1964., 2 (Box 89)
    - Murphy, John Cullen, 20th c., 1 (Box 89)
    - Murphy, Stanley, 20th c., 1 (Box 89)
    - Murray, Elizabeth, 1940-., 1 (Box 89)
    - Myers, Jerome, 1867-1940., 3 (Box 89)
  - Individual Artists (Box 89)
    - MacIver, Loren, 1909-., 7 (Box 89)
    - Malbone, Edward Greene, 1777-1807., 3 (Box 89)
    - Mangravite, Peppino, 1896-., 5 (Box 89)
    - Man Ray, 1890-1976., 17 (Box 89)
    - Marca-Relli, Corrado di, 1913-., 5 (Box 89)
    - Marden, Brice, 1938-., 8 (Box 89)
    - Mare, John, 1739-?., 3 (Box 89)
    - Margules, De Hirsh, 1899-., 3 (Box 89)
    - Marin, John, 1870-1953., Total of 61 photographs. (Box 89–90)
      - Location Unknown., 24 (Box 90)
      - Private Collections, 13 (Box 90)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 9 (Box 90)
      - New Haven, 6 (Box 90)
      - New York, 9 (Box 90)
    - Marinsky, Harry, 1909-., 5 (Box 91)
    - Marsh, Reginald, 1898-1954., Total of 36 photographs. (Box 91)
      - Location Unknown, 18 (Box 91)
      - New Haven, 5 (Box 91)
      - New York, 13 (Box 91)
    - Martin, Fletcher, 1904-1979., 8 (Box 91)
    - Martin, Homer D., 1836-1897., 11 (Box 92)
    - Mattson, Henry, 1887-1971., 4 (Box 92)
    - Maurer, Alfred Henry, 1869-1932., 5 (Box 92)
    - McCrady, John, 1911-1968., 7 (Box 92)
    - McFee, Henry Lee, 1886-1953., 9 (Box 92)
    - Melchers, Gari, 1860-1932., 12 (Box 92)
    - Meltsner, Paul, 1905-., 3 (Box 92)
    - Metcalf, Willard LeRoy, 1858-1925., 10 (Box 93)
    - Miller, Alfred Jacob, 1810-1874., 5 (Box 93)
    - Miller, Kenneth Hayes, 1876-1952., 8 (Box 93)
    - Minor, Robert Crannell, 1840-1904., 7 (Box 93)
    - Mitchell, Joan, 1926-1992., 12 (Box 93)
    - Moran, Thomas, 1837-1926., 30 (Box 93)
    - Morley, Malcolm, 1931-., 8 (Box 94)
    - Morris, George L.K., 1905-1975., 10 (Box 94)
    - Morris, Kyle, 1917-., 3 (Box 94)
    - Morse, Samuel F.B., 1791-1872., Total of 43 photographs. (Box 94)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 21 (Box 94)
      - New Haven, 12 (Box 94)
      - New York, 10 (Box 94)
    - Motherwell, Robert, 1915-., 10 (Box 95)
    - Motherwell, Robert, continued., 21 (Box 95)
    - Moulthrop, Reuben, 1763-1814., 7 (Box 95)
    - Mount, William Sidney, 1807-1863., Total of 31 photographs. (Box 95)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 21 (Box 95)
      - New York, 10 (Box 95)
    - Murphy, John Francis, 1853-1921., 12 (Box 96)
    - Murray, Elizabeth, 1940-., 11 (Box 96)
- N (Box 96)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "N" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Na-Ni., 17 (Box 96)
    - Nack, Kenneth, 1923-?., 1 (Box 96)
    - Nadelman, Eli, 1885-1946., 1 (Box 96)
    - Nadin, Peter, 1954-., 1 (Box 96)
    - Nesbitt, Lowel, 20th c., 1 (Box 96)
    - Nevius, Thia, 20th c., 1 (Box 96)
    - Newby, Ruby Warren, 1886-?., 1 (Box 96)
    - Newell, James Michael, 1900-?., 1 (Box 96)
    - Newman, Henry Roderick, 1843-1917., 1 (Box 96)
    - Nichols, Dale, 20th c., 1 (Box 96)
    - Nielsen, Kay, 1882-1924., 1 (Box 96)
    - Nielson, John, 1881-1954., 1 (Box 96)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: No-Nu., 11 (Box 96)
    - Noel, Georges, 20th c., 1 (Box 96)
    - Noel, Leon, 1807-1869., 1 (Box 96)
    - North, Noah, 1809-1880., 2 (Box 96)
    - Nozkowski, Thomas, 1944-., 1 (Box 96)
    - Nutt, Jim, 1938-., 1 (Box 96)
  - Individual Artists (Box 96)
    - Nash, John Northcote, 1893-., 5 (Box 96)
    - Natkin, Robert, 1930-., 9 (Box 96)
    - Neagle, John, 1796-1865., 16 (Box 97)
    - Neel, Alice, 1900-1984., 5 (Box 97)
    - Neilson, Raymond Perry Rogers, 1881-1964., 7 (Box 97)
    - Newman, Barnett, 1905-1970., 17 (Box 97)
    - Newman, Robert Loftin, 1827-1912., 4 (Box 97)
    - Noble, Thomas Satterwhite, 1835- 1907., 4 (Box 97)
    - Noland, Kenneth, 1924-., 19 (Box 97)
    - Novros, David, 1941-., 5 (Box 98)
- O (Box 98)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "O" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: O-Ou., 19 (Box 98)
    - Ohlson, Doug, 1936-., 1 (Box 98)
    - Okada, Kenzo, 1902-?., 4 (Box 98)
    - Oliviera, Nathan, 1928-?., 1 (Box 98)
    - Ortman, George, 1926-?., 3 (Box 98)
    - Osborne, Elizabeth, 1936-?., 1 (Box 98)
    - Ossorio, Alfonso, 1916-?., 3 (Box 98)
    - Osver, Arthur, 1912-?., 3 (Box 98)
    - Otis, Bass, 1784-1861., 2 (Box 98)
    - Outerbridge, Paul, 1896-?., 1 (Box 98)
    - Otto, Heinrich, 18th c., 1 (Box 98)
  - Individual Artists (Box 98)
    - Oakley, Violet, 1874-1961., 5 (Box 98)
    - O'Hara, Eliot, 1890-., 5 (Box 98)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986., 98 (Box 98–99)
      - General, 5 (Box 99)
      - Location Unknown, 39 (Box 99)
      - Private Collection, 12 (Box 99)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 23 (Box 99)
      - New York, 19 (Box 99)
    - Oldenburg, Claes, 1929-., 11 (Box 100)
    - Olitski, Jules, 1922-., 11 (Box 100)
- P (Box 100)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "P" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Pa., 21 (Box 100)
    - Pace, Stephen, 1918-?., 1 (Box 100)
    - Parcell, Malcolm, 1876-?., 2 (Box 100)
    - Park, David, 1911-1960., 2 (Box 100)
    - Parton, Arthur, 1842-1914., 1 (Box 100)
    - Parker, Raymond, 1922-?., 3 (Box 100)
    - Parker, Robert Andrew, 1927-?., 1 (Box 100)
    - Parshall, Douglass, 20th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Partridge, Joseph, 19th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Partridge, Nehemiah, 18th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Paschke, Edward, 1937-., 2 (Box 100)
    - Paternosto, Caesar, 20th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Patterson, Charles, 19th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Paul, Jeremiah, act. 1791-1820., 2 (Box 100)
    - Paxton, William McGregor, 1869-1941., 1 (Box 100)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Pe., 22 (Box 100)
    - Peale, Anna Claypole, 1791-1878., 1 (Box 100)
    - Peale, James, 19th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865., 1 (Box 100)
    - Peale, Sarah M., 1800-1885., 1 (Box 100)
    - Peck, Sheldon, 19th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Pelham, Peter, 1663-1751., 3 (Box 100)
    - Pennell, Joseph, 1860-1926., 2 (Box 100)
    - Perlis, Don, 20th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Perry, Enoch Wood, 1931-1915., 1 (Box 100)
    - Perry, Lilla Cabot, 1848-1933., 4 (Box 100)
    - Persac, Marie Adrien, 19th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Peterdi, Gabor, 20th c., 1 (Box 100)
    - Peterson, Jane, 1876-1955., 1 (Box 100)
    - Pettet, William, 1942-., 3 (Box 100)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ph-Pi., 18 (Box 101)
    - Philipp, Robert, 1895-?., 1 (Box 101)
    - Phillips, Ammi, 1788-1865., 3 (Box 101)
    - Phillips, Bert Geer, 1868-1956., 1 (Box 101)
    - Pickens, Alton, 1917-?., 1 (Box 101)
    - Picknell, William Lamb, 1854-1897., 1 (Box 101)
    - Pierie, Captain William, 19th c., 3 (Box 101)
    - Pindell, Howardena, 1943-., 1 (Box 101)
    - Pine, Robert, 1730-1788., 3 (Box 101)
    - Pinney, Eunice, 1820-1849., 3 (Box 101)
    - Piper, Jane, 1916-?., 1 (Box 101)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Pl-Po., 25 (Box 101)
    - Plagens, Peter, 1939-., 1 (Box 101)
    - Plamondon, Peter, 1939-., 1 (Box 101)
    - Plate, Walter, 1925-?., 1 (Box 101)
    - Pleissner, Ogden M., 1905-?., 2 (Box 101)
    - Plellis, Charles D., 20th c., 1 (Box 101)
    - Plotkin, Linda, 1938-., 1 (Box 101)
    - Poole, Abram, 19th c., 1 (Box 101)
    - Pope, Alexander, 1849-1924., 3 (Box 101)
    - Porter, Katherine, 1941-., 1 (Box 101)
    - Porter, Rufus, 1792-1884., 1 (Box 101)
    - Portzline, Francis, 19th c., 2 (Box 101)
    - Posen, Stephen, 1939-., 2 (Box 101)
    - Post, William Merritt, 1856-1935., 1 (Box 101)
    - Potter, William Jr., 19th c., 1 (Box 101)
    - Potthast, Edward, 1857-1927., 2 (Box 101)
    - Pousette-Dart, Richard, 1916-?., 3 (Box 101)
    - Powell, W.H., 1823-1879., 1 (Box 101)
    - Powers, Asahel, 1813-1843., 1 (Box 101)
    - Pozzatti, Rudy, 1925-?., 1 (Box 101)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Pr-Pu., 23 (Box 102)
    - Prendergast, Charles E., 1868-?, 2 (Box 102)
    - Prentice, Levi Wells, 1851-1935., 2 (Box 102)
    - Preston, Dickinson, 1891-1930., 1 (Box 102)
    - Prestopino, Gregorio, 1907-., 3 (Box 102)
    - Price, C.S., 1874-1950., 3 (Box 102)
    - Price, Kenneth, 20th c., 1 (Box 102)
    - Price, William, 18th c., 2 (Box 102)
    - Priebe, Karl, 20th c., 1 (Box 102)
    - Pringle, James, 19th c., 1 (Box 102)
    - Prior, William, 1806-1873., 3 (Box 102)
    - Pryor, Warrant, 19th c., 1 (Box 102)
    - Pushman, Hovsep, 20th c., 1 (Box 102)
    - Putnam, Wallace, 1899-?., 1 (Box 102)
    - Pyle, Howard, 1853-1911., 1 (Box 102)
  - Individual Artists (Box 102)
    - Page, William, 1811-1885., 7 (Box 102)
    - Palmer, William, 1763-1790., 6 (Box 102)
    - Pape, Eric, 1870-1938., 4 (Box 102)
    - Parrish, Maxfield, 1870-1966., 6 (Box 102)
    - Pascin, Jules, 1885-1930., 10 (Box 102)
    - Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827., total of 55 photographs. (Box 102–103)
      - Location Unknown, 3 (Box 103)
      - Private Collection, 4 (Box 103)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 19 (Box 103)
      - New York, 10 (Box 103)
      - Philadelphia, 19 (Box 103)
    - Peale, James, 1749-1831., 11 (Box 103)
    - Peale, Raphaelle, 1774-1825., 12 (Box 104)
    - Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860., 21 (Box 104)
    - Pearlstein, Philip, 1924-., 15 (Box 104)
    - Peirce, Waldo, 1884-1970., 11 (Box 104)
    - Pereira, Irene Rice, 1907-1971., 10 (Box 105)
    - Peto, John Frederick, 1854-1907., 15 (Box 105)
    - Phillips, Marjorie, 1894-., 8 (Box 105)
    - Pickett, Joseph, 1848-1918., 6 (Box 105)
    - Pippin, Horace, 1888-1946., 4 (Box 105)
    - Pollet, Joseph, 1897-1979., 4 (Box 105)
    - Pollock, Jackson, 1912-1956., Total of 73 photographs. (Box 105–106)
      - 1930-1939, 5 (Box 106)
      - 1940-1944, 12 (Box 106)
      - 1945-1949, 9 (Box 106)
      - 1945-1949, cont., 20 (Box 106)
      - 1950-1959, 27 (Box 106)
    - Poons, Larry, 1937-., 9 (Box 107)
    - Poor, Henry V., 1888-1970., 11 (Box 107)
    - Porter, Fairfield, 1907-1975., 6 (Box 107)
    - Pratt, Matthew, 1734-1805., 6 (Box 107)
    - Prendergast, Maurice, 1859-1924., Total of 47 photographs. (Box 107)
      - Location Unknown, 14 (Box 107)
      - Private Collection, 2 (Box 107)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 16 (Box 107)
      - Washington, 15 (Box 107)
- Q (Box 107)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "Q" artists.
  - Individual Artists (Box 108)
    - Quartley, Arthur, 1839-1886., 1 (Box 108)
    - Quaytman, Harvey, 1937-., 1 (Box 108)
    - Quidor, John, 1801-1881., 7 (Box 108)
    - Quidor, John, 1801-1881, cont., 11 (Box 108)
    - Quinn, Edmond Thomas, 1868-1929., 1 (Box 108)
- R (Box 108)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "R" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ra., 14 (Box 108)
    - Raffael, Joseph, 1933-., 3 (Box 108)
    - Ramos, Mel, 1935-., 2 (Box 108)
    - Rand, Ellen Emmet, 1876-?., 1 (Box 108)
    - Rand, Paul, 20th c., 3 (Box 108)
    - Ranger, Henry Ward, 1858-1916., 1 (Box 108)
    - Ranney, William Tylee, 1813-1857., 3 (Box 108)
    - Rasmusen, J., 19th c., 1 (Box 108)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Re-Ri., 19 (Box 108)
    - Read, Thomas B., 1822-1872, 1 (Box 108)
    - Read, William, 1607-1679., 1 (Box 108)
    - Rebay, Hilla, 1895-?., 1 (Box 108)
    - Redell, Raymond, 20th c., 1 (Box 108)
    - Reed, David, 20th c., 1 (Box 108)
    - Reed, Robert, 20th c., 1 (Box 108)
    - Refregier, Anton, 1905-., 1 (Box 108)
    - Regensburg, Sophy P., 20th c., 1 (Box 108)
    - Reid, Robert, 1862-1929., 2 (Box 108)
    - Reinhardt, Siegfried, 1926-?., 2 (Box 108)
    - Rhymes, Judy, 1954-., 1 (Box 108)
    - Richer, H., 19th c., 1 (Box 108)
    - Rifka, Judy, 20th c., 1 (Box 108)
    - Rimmer,William, 1816-1879., 1 (Box 108)
    - Rindisbacher, Peter, 1806-1834., 1 (Box 108)
    - Ringgold, Faith, 20th c., 2 (Box 108)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ro., 33 (Box 109)
    - Robbins, Bruce, 1948-., 1 (Box 109)
    - Robertson, Archibald, 1765-1835., 1 (Box 109)
    - Rochester, Jacqueline, 1952-., 1 (Box 109)
    - Rockwell, Norman, 1894-1978., 2 (Box 109)
    - Roesen, Severin, 1815-1871., 3 (Box 109)
    - Rogers, Barbara, 1937-., 1 (Box 109)
    - Ropes, Joseph, 1812-1885., 3 (Box 109)
    - Rose, Guy, 19th c., 2 (Box 109)
    - Rose, Herman, 20th c., 2 (Box 109)
    - Rosenberg, Samuel, 1896-?., 1 (Box 109)
    - Rosenborg, Ralph, 1910-?., 2 (Box 109)
    - Rosenthal, Toby E., 1848-1917., 1 (Box 109)
    - Roszak, Theodore, 1907-?., 1 (Box 109)
    - Rothermell, Peter F., 1817-1895., 2 (Box 109)
    - Rothschild, Judith, 20th c., 2 (Box 109)
    - Rouland, Orlando, 19th c., 2 (Box 109)
    - Rowe, Nellie Mae, 1900-1982., 1 (Box 109)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ru-Ry., 18 (Box 109)
    - Ruley, Ellis, 1882-1959., 3 (Box 109)
    - Ruscha, Ed, 20th c., 1 (Box 109)
    - Ruscha, Robert, 1937-., 1 (Box 109)
    - Rusnack, Diane, 20th c., 1 (Box 109)
    - Ryan, Anne, 1889-1954., 2 (Box 109)
    - Ryder, Chauncey, 19th c., 3 (Box 109)
    - Ryder, Platt Powell, 1821-1896., 1 (Box 109)
  - Individual Artists (Box 109)
    - Rattner, Abraham, 1895-1978., 18 (Box 109)
    - Rauschenberg, Robert, 1925-., 29 (Box 110)
    - Rauschenberg, Robert, 1925-, continued., 17 (Box 110)
    - Reindel, Edna, 1900-., 3 (Box 110)
    - Reinhardt, Ad, 1913-1967., 11 (Box 110)
    - Remington, Frederic, 1861-1909., 20 (Box 110)
    - Resnick, Milton, 1917-., 5 (Box 110)
    - Richards, William Trost, 1833-1905., 6 (Box 111)
    - Rivers, Larry, 1925-., 3 (Box 111)
    - Rivers, Larry, 1925-, cont., 11 (Box 111)
    - Robinson, Boardman, 1876-1952., 4 (Box 111)
    - Robinson, Theodore, 1852-1896., 11 (Box 111)
    - Roerich, Nicolas, 1874-1947., 3 (Box 111)
    - Rosenquist, James, 1933-., 14 (Box 111)
    - Rosenthal, Doris, 1885-1971., 3 (Box 111)
    - Rossiter, Thomas Prichard, 1818- 1871., 5 (Box 111)
    - Rothenberg, Susan, 1945-., 5 (Box 111)
    - Rothko, Mark, 1903-1970., Total of 58 photographs. (Box 111–112)
      - Undated, 1 (Box 112)
      - 1930-1949, 11 (Box 112)
      - 1950-1959, 34 (Box 112)
      - 1960-1969, 12 (Box 112)
    - Russell, Charles, 1864-1926., 11 (Box 112)
    - Russell, Morgan, 1886-1953., 5 (Box 112)
    - Ryder, Albert Pinkham, 1847-1926., Total of 58 photographs. (Box 112–113)
      - Location Unknown, 7 (Box 113)
      - Private Collection, 1 (Box 113)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 20 (Box 113)
      - New York, 11 (Box 113)
      - Washington D.C., 11 (Box 113)
        - Individual Repositories, Washington: The Phillips Collection, 8 (Box 113)
    - Ryman, Robert, 1930-., 6 (Box 113)
- S (Box 113)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "S" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Sa., 13 (Box 114)
    - Sage, Kay, 1926-?., 2 (Box 114)
    - Salemme, Attilo, 1911-1955., 2 (Box 114)
    - Salt, John, 1937-., 1 (Box 114)
    - Samaras, Lucas, 1936-., 2 (Box 114)
    - Sander, Ludwig, 20th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Satra, 19th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Saunders, George, 1807-1863., 1 (Box 114)
    - Saunders, Raymond, 1934-., 2 (Box 114)
    - Sawyier, Paul, 1868-1917., 1 (Box 114)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Sc., 17 (Box 114)
    - Schillos, Siri, 1953-., 1 (Box 114)
    - Schmidt, Katherine,1898-?,., 2 (Box 114)
    - Schnabel, Julian, 1951-., 3 (Box 114)
    - Schnoover, Frank, 20th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Schonzeit, Ben, 20th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Schrag, Karl, 1912-?., 1 (Box 114)
    - Schreyvogel, Charles, 1861-1912., 2 (Box 114)
    - Schussele, Christian, 1824-1879., 1 (Box 114)
    - Schwab, Eloisa, 1894-?., 1 (Box 114)
    - Schweitzer, Gertrude, 1901-?., 2 (Box 114)
    - Scott, William, 1884-?., 1 (Box 114)
    - Scully, Sean, 1945-., 1 (Box 114)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Se-Sk., 23 (Box 114)
    - Seas, Charles, 1818-1867., 1 (Box 114)
    - Sebron, H., 1801-1879., 1 (Box 114)
    - Seligmann, Kurt, 20th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Semmel, Joan, 20th c., 2 (Box 114)
    - Serra, Richard, 1939-., 2 (Box 114)
    - Seyffert, Leopold, 1887-?., 2 (Box 114)
    - Seymour, Samuel, 1797-1822., 3 (Box 114)
    - Shapiro, David, 1916-?., 1 (Box 114)
    - Shatter, Susan, 20th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Shields, Alan, 20th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Shimin, Symeon, 1902-?., 2 (Box 114)
    - Shirlaw, Walter, 1838-1909., 2 (Box 114)
    - Shore, Henrietta, 1880-1963., 1 (Box 114)
    - Simitiere, Pierre, 1736-1784., 1 (Box 114)
    - Sjoholm, Karen, 1951-., 1 (Box 114)
    - Skolnick, Anne, 20th c., 1 (Box 114)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Sm., 14 (Box 114)
    - Smibert, Nathaniel, 1735-1756., 1 (Box 114)